Right?
So we have all our sprites in order, and we're ready to start working on our gameplay mechanics.
And to start off with, let's get our player sprite working.
Now, just so we can focus on one thing, let's quickly hide these other sprites by just clicking this
icon here, and we can do the same for this.
And there we go.
Now let's move our main player sprite down the screen somewhere near -1 to 5.
There we go.
So we have our player sprite to be able to move from left to right on the screen.
And thankfully we know pretty well how to do this because of our last project.
You remember.
So let's just bring in the basic blocks once again.
The when start forever and if and also the if else block.
So to get our player to move left or right, we can grab two of these key pressed code blocks and change
it to left and the other to right.
Then we can put them into each of these if inputs and structure it just like we did before.
Now then variable, we add in our and change x by all and point our player.
Let's duplicate it.
So here it feels.
Basically I'm skiing this so we can have two separate scripts.
One that controls our pointing direction and the other that controls our movement.
Doing this keeps our code a lot more organized by ensuring each script we have doesn't try to do too
many things.
This is called Componentization in programming, and it's a very important concept as it also makes
our code more reusable as we can create scripts that do one certain thing well, and then we can use
the script in different projects compared to if we were just to have one long entangled script that
was specific only to one project, like we click, we could use the hyphen script somewhere else.
But if it had the point direct variable with the movement instead, it would be we can just difficult
to use in it.
So other code.
So guys, let's start with Liz and her movement script and stuff.
So if Rive clicked Willow change X by two you know and of some if left arrow key I see we can listen
x by in yeah ten often and clicking it's less.
As you can see it works.
And yeah just a bit rough.
Fine actually I'll be improving this soon.
Apex make it look more golden.
But for now just you'll roll with this gets out.
So let's get out direction animation working now.
Basically, like we did before, if right arrow clicked, we can add in this point direction and point
to the right and the left arrow clicked.
We can point to the left just like that.
So let's try that out.
Okay, that's not right.
And if you remember from before, because our sprite's costume position is not facing right, we have
this problem.
Now instead of changing the costume direction in the editor like we did before, let's look at another
solution.
Here we can just set point right to 105 and point left to 75 and forward to 90 degrees and clicking
play.
You see, this works, although it might be better practice to change it like we did before.
But as I say, if it ain't broke, don't fix it.
So with that done, all we need to do is switch the costume like this is ever good enough.
So if we click that arrow, we can see a guy in costume to right?
And the, uh, to the fourth condition last, the left to right costume.
Any of those.
Just like that is easy.
So nothing play park as you can see it.
Or a lot better of it.
I encourage you to play.
He's like code so that you can maybe tweak it them even better.
So because we're only getting started.